So visual assessment is really simple.
إذن، فالتقييم البصري بسيط للغاية.
It's just looking at your dataset in its entirety in whatever program you like to use.
وهو مجرد النظر إلى مجموعة البيانات الخاصة بكم في مجملها في أي برنامج ترغبون في استخدامه.
For example, in Pandas here.
على سبيل المثال، في Pandas الموجود هنا.
So we've already gathered the data here.
لذلك قمنا بالفعل بجمع البيانات هنا.
We've imported the Pandas library and read the CSV files into
لقد قمنا بالفعل باستيراد مكتبة Pandas وقراءة ملفات CSV في
these data frames: patients, treatments, adverse reactions.
إطارات البيانات هذه: المرضى، والعلاجات، والتفاعلات الضارة.
And now we can visually assess.
والآن يمكننا تقييم بصري.
We can just look through each table.
يمكننا فقط النظر من خلال كل جدول.
But because Pandas collapses rows here and scrolling in a Jupyter Notebook
ولكن لأن Pandas يطوي الصفوف هنا فالتمرير إلى Jupyter Notebook
is finicky as I'm frustratingly displaying here,
صعب، فأنا أعرض هنا بشك محبط.
I tend to prefer to open files in a spreadsheet application like Google sheets or Excel.
وأفضّل فتح الملفات في تطبيق جداول البيانات مثل Google sheets أو Excel.
Here's Google sheets. Patients.CSV, treatments.CSV and adverse_reactions.CSV.
هنا Google sheets. Patients.CSV وtreatment.CSV و adverse_reactions.CSV.
But some datasets are so large that,
لكن بعض مجموعات البيانات كبيرة جدًا
spreadsheet programs crash when trying to open them,
بحيث تتعطل برامج جداول البيانات عند محاولة فتحها،
so your hand is forced into using something like Pandas sometimes.
لذا تضطر إلى استخدام شيء مثل spreadsheet في بعض الأحيان.
And again, we can just scroll through here and look for stuff.
ومرة أخرى، يمكننا التمرير من هنا والبحث عن الأشياء.
We can look for both quality and tidiness issues.
يمكننا البحث عن كل من مشكلات الجودة والترتيب.
So you could start by looking for things like number of columns,
لذلك يمكنكم البدء بالبحث عن أشياء مثل عدد الأعمدة،
what the column headers are,
ورؤوس الأعمدة،
how many rows there are,
وعدد الصفوف،
what each row represents,
وما يمثله كل صف،
what other types of values in the cells,
وما أنواع القيم الأخرى في الخلايا،
like data types, integers,
مثل أنواع البيانات والأعداد الصحيحة
strings, floating point, et cetera.
والسلاسل والنقطة العائمة …إلخ.
But that isn't that efficient in visual assessment.
لكن ليس بهذه الكفاءة في التقييم البصري.
That's best done using programmatic assessment.
هذا أفضل ما يمكن القيام به باستخدام التقييم البرمجي.
So what is visual assessment good for?
إذن متى يكون التقييم البصري جيدًا؟
Visual assessment is great for getting acquainted with
يعتبر التقييم البصري أمرًا رائعًا للتعرّف على
the dataset and just trying to understand what it's all about,
مجموعة البيانات ومحاولة فهم ما يدور حولها،
like acquiring a mental picture of it.
مثل الحصول على صورة ذهنية لها.
Also, a lot of the time assessing is driven by the problem you want to solve,
أيضًا، فإن الكثير من تقييم الوقت يكون مدفوعًا بالمشكلة التي تريد حلها،
like checking the values in the columns and rows you plan on using in your analysis.
مثل التحقق من القيم في الأعمدة والصفوف التي تخططون لاستخدامها في تحليلكم.
Like hba1c_change for example.
مثل hba1c_change على سبيل المثال.
This can be effective in both visual assessment and programmatic.
هذا يمكن أن يكون فعالًا في كل من التقييم البصري والبرمجي.
Non-directed visual assessment can be useful too.
يمكن أن يكون التقييم البصري غير الموجّه مفيدًا أيضًا.
Just scrolling aimlessly and stumbling upon issues,
فقط قم بالتمرير دون عوائق والبحث عن المشكلات،
then dialing in on something once you have more of a clue of what issue you've spotted.
ثم طلب شيء ما عندما يكون لديك المزيد من المعلومات حول المشكلة التي لاحظتها.
At that point you can use more pinpointed assessments whether visual or programmatic.
عند هذه النقطة ، يمكنك استخدام تقييمات أكثر تحديدًا سواء كانت مرئية أو برمجية.
So let's go back to the first thing that visual assessment was good for,
لذا دعونا نعود إلى الشيء أول الذي كان يفيد فيه التقييم البصري،
getting acquainted with the meaning of the dataset.
والتعرف على معنى مجموعة البيانات.
So let's do that now. You'll look through the patients treatments and
لذا، دعونا نفعل ذلك الآن. ستنظر من خلال علاجات المرضى
adverse reactions table and really start to understand what each column represents.
والتفاعلات الضارة وتبدأ حقًا في فهم ما يمثله كل عمود.